3DOF Confined-Space Precision Manipulator
Novel Algorithms for 6DOF-level Precision
Innovation 1: Safe Zone Singularity Avoidance
Real-time damping adjustment, zero divergence
Innovation 2: Minimum Jerk Trajectory
Smooth motion with optimal jerk minimization
Innovation 3: Force/Position Hybrid Control
Impedance-based manipulation with touch feedback
Innovation 4: Adaptive Impedance Control
Dynamic stiffness 50-200 N/m for varying tasks
Task 1-3: Basic Positioning and Path Tracking
5-Point Reaching, Square, Circle - 100% success
Task 4-8: Advanced Trajectory Control
Figure-8, Spiral, Star, Heart, Spiral Star
Task 9-10: Manipulation and Navigation
Force-Controlled Grasp, Obstacle Avoidance
Task 11-15: Dynamic and Integration
Fast Switching, Precision Assembly, Composite
Performance: 15/15 tasks, 100% success rate
Average error < 15mm, Control at 500Hz
3DOF achieves 6DOF-level precision
Minimalist hardware, maximum capability
Industrial Applications:
Confined-space assembly, Precision manufacturing
UUID: d2f04863-5683-4e20-bd39-32f0cf339dc2
FFAI Robothon 2026 - Freestyle Category